reservations.com 2013-06-22

# Privacy Policy | Travelocity

As a user of Travelocity's web sites, mobile applications and services (collectively, the "Travelocity Service"), you are in control of your travel-planning. We know you want to remain in control of your personal information as well. As one of the pioneers in online travel, we realize that earning and retaining your trust is of paramount importance and it's a responsibility we take very seriously. 

That's why we've provided this Privacy Policy, which sets forth Travelocity's policies regarding the collection, use and protection of the personal information of those using Travelocity Service. Personal information means information that can be linked to a specific individual, such as name, address, telephone number, e-mail address and credit card number. 

We encourage you to review our Privacy Policy, and become familiar with it, but you should know that **we do not sell or rent our customers' personal information to third parties**. 

Please note that we review our Privacy Policy from time to time, and we make changes to the policy in connection with that review. Therefore, you may wish to periodically review this page to make sure that you have the current version. 

This Privacy Policy explains the following: 

  * What personal information we collect and how we use it
  * With whom your personal information is shared
  * How you can opt-out of receiving our promotional e-mails 
  * How you can update or correct your personal information 
  * What safeguards we have in place to protect your personal information 
  * Other information you should know about your privacy

What personal information does Travelocity collect and how is it used?  

You are not required to provide any personal information to us unless and until you choose to make a purchase or sign up for one of our e-mail newsletters or other services as described below. We do not knowingly permit the Travelocity Service to be used by any person under the age of eighteen and we do not knowingly collect any personal information from children (meaning those younger than thirteen years of age). A valid credit or debit card is required to make a purchase using the Travelocity Service. 

_Making a Purchase_  
In order to book travel using the Travelocity Service, you must provide us with certain personal information such as your name, your credit or debit card number and expiration date, your credit or debit card billing address, your telephone number, your e-mail address and the name or names of any person(s) traveling with you. We may also ask you for other personal information, such as your frequent traveler numbers. We require this information so that we can process, fulfill and confirm your reservations and transactions and keep you informed of their status. If you are making a reservation for one or more other travelers, you will need to make sure that each of these other travelers agrees, in advance, that you may disclose their personal information to us. For your convenience, we make certain information about your reservation available to you or other persons authorized by you to receive such information. For example, if you forget your flight number, you or another person authorized by you may retrieve that information from us after confirming your or their identity. 

_Express Consent To Receive Pre-Recorded And Text Messages_  
When you book travel using the Travelocity Service, you must provide us with a contact telephone number. We will use that telephone number in the event that we need to inform you of changes or other matters that may affect your booking or trip, such as changes due to flight delays, inclement weather, and cancellations. We may use an automatic telephone dialing system, artificial or prerecorded voice messages, or text messages to provide you with such updates. When you provide us with a mobile telephone number as the contact number for a trip, you agree that you are providing us with your express consent to receive prerecorded voice messages or text messages from Travelocity or our third party suppliers and content providers ("Third Party Suppliers") related to your booking. If you do not wish to receive these trip updates on your mobile phone, please provide us with another telephone number. 

_Member Registration_  
If you choose to register as a member of Travelocity, you must provide your name, address, telephone number, e-mail address, a unique login name (if different from your e-mail address), password, and password validation, and a password hint to help you remember your password. We collect this information for several reasons including: (i) personal identification; (ii) to complete air, hotel, car, and other reservations; (iii) to allow us to contact you for customer service purposes, if necessary; (iv) to customize the content of the Travelocity Service to meet your specific needs; and (v) to make product improvements to the Travelocity Service. In addition, we need your e-mail address to confirm your new member registration and each reservation you make using the Travelocity Service. 

_Member Profile_  
As a Travelocity member, you can choose to complete your online profile by providing us with travel preferences, frequent-traveler or affinity numbers, credit-card billing information, paper ticket delivery address, and other information, which may include personal information. This information is primarily used to assist you in making reservations quickly without having to type in the same information again. For example, you can store your airline frequent-flyer numbers so that when your make a reservation on that airline using the Travelocity Service, we can automatically complete the frequent-flyer number input box for you. 

_TSA Secure Flight_  
Under the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) Secure Flight program, most air passengers are now required to provide their full name, date of birth, and gender (plus redress number, when applicable). If you are making a reservation for travelers other than yourself, you should make sure each traveler agrees, in advance, that you may disclose their personal information to us.

Secure Flight is a federally mandated program administered by the TSA. The privacy notice of the TSA is as follows:

> The Transportation Security Administration of the U.S. Department of Homeland Security requires aircraft operators to collect information from you for purposes of watch list screening, under the authority of 49 U.S.C. section 114, and the Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004. Providing this information is voluntary; however, if it is not provided, you may be subject to additional screening or denied transport or authorization to enter a sterile area. TSA may share information you provide with law enforcement or intelligence agencies or others under its published system of records notice. For more on TSA Privacy policies, or to view the system of records notice and the privacy impact assessment, please see TSA's Web site at [www.tsa.gov](http://www.tsa.gov/).

_Newsletters and FareWatcher Plus SM_  
Travelocity's "Roaming Gnome Recommends" and other newsletters and our FareWatcher Plus service are optional communications you may choose to subscribe to that keep you up to date with the latest special travel deals and low airfares. FareWatcher Plus tracks the prices of airline tickets to your favorite places. When the price for one of your favorite trips changes based on your preferences, Travelocity will notify you of the change via e-mail. Your e-mail address and preferred round trip city pairs are necessary to receive FareWatcher Plus e-mails. 

_Online Surveys_  
Travelocity values opinions and comments from members, so we frequently conduct online surveys. Participation in these surveys is optional. Typically, we aggregate the information we collect and use it to make improvements to the Travelocity Service and to develop appealing content, features and promotions for customers. Survey participants are anonymous unless otherwise stated in the survey. 

_Promotions & Sweepstakes_  
Travelocity frequently sponsors promotions and sweepstakes to give customers the opportunity to win great travel and travel-related prizes. The information we collect for such activities can include historical bookings made, historical shopping behavior, contact information and survey questions. We use contact information to notify contest winners and we use survey information to develop promotions and product improvements to the Travelocity Service. 

_Third Parties Offering Promotions, Products, or Services_  
Travelocity may share your personal information with third parties when you engage in certain activities on our site that are sponsored by third parties, such as electing to receive information or communications from a third party (such as a hotel company or a tourism board for a particular destination), or electing to participate in contests, sweepstakes, games or other programs sponsored in whole or in part by a third party. Travelocity may also share your personal information when you respond to promotional materials from Travelocity and authorize a third party to use your personal information for purposes such as sending you additional promotional materials, providing you a product or service, or entering you in a contest, sweepstakes or game. We refer to all of these activities and requests as "Sponsored Activities." When you participate in Sponsored Activities, you will either be required or requested to agree that Travelocity may send your personal information (such as, in some cases, your mailing address or e-mail address) to the sponsor, and the sponsor may use your personal information in accordance with the sponsor's privacy practices. _In each case described in this section, Travelocity will only share your personal information after receiving your consent_. You should know that when Travelocity shares your personal information with a third party under any circumstance described in this section, your personal information will become permanently subject to the privacy policy of the third party, and the third party will not be restricted by Travelocity's Privacy Policy with respect to its use and further sharing of your personal information. 

_Automatic Logging of Session Data_  
We automatically log generic information about your computer and your computer's connection to the Internet, which we call "session data". Session data consists of things such as device information, IP address, operating system and browser software information, and the activities conducted by the user while using the Travelocity Service. An IP address is a number that lets computers attached to the Internet, such as our web servers, know where to send data back to the user, such as the pages of the site the user wishes to view. We collect session data because it helps us analyze such things as what items visitors are likely to click on most, the way visitors are clicking through the site, how many visitors are surfing to various pages on the site, how long visitors to the site are staying and how often they are visiting. It also helps us diagnose problems with our servers and lets us better administer our systems. It is possible to determine from an IP address a visitor's Internet Service Provider (ISP) and the approximate geographic location of his or her point of connectivity. We may also use some session data, such as the pages you visited on our site, to send you e-mail messages (such as "Good Day to Buy") focused on destinations that you may be interested in, unless you had previously opted out of receiving such messages. We also use session data to help prevent fraud or unauthorized use of our site. 

_Cookies_  
"Cookies" are small pieces of information that are stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive. Cookies allow us to serve you better and more efficiently. Travelocity uses cookies to personalize your experience using the Travelocity Service. These types of cookies allow you to log in without having to type your log-in name each time (only your password is needed), let us know if you are a FareWatcher Plus participant or a Travelocity VIP, your preferred language and departure city, and so forth. We may also use such cookies to display an advertisement to you while you are using the Travelocity Service or to send you a "Good Day to Buy" email (or similar emails -- assuming you have not opted-out) focusing on destinations that we think you might be interested in.

Most web browsers automatically accept cookies. By changing the options on your web browser or using certain software programs, you can control how and whether cookies will be accepted by your browser. Travelocity supports your right to block any unwanted Internet activity, especially that of unscrupulous websites. However, blocking Travelocity cookies may disable certain features on our site and may make it impossible to purchase or use certain services available on the site. Please note that it is possible to block cookie activity from certain web sites while permitting cookies from sites you trust, like Travelocity. 

_Advertising Data Collected By Us to Display Relevant Advertising to You_   
Travelocity is committed to providing you with relevant content and information. To do this, we may, through cookies and other technologies, collect information about your travel-related searches, such as whether you are looking for flights or hotel rooms. We use this information, together with other information we have collected, to display ads to you on our website or elsewhere online, that match your apparent interests. So, for example, if you search for a hotel room in Hawaii using the Travelocity Service, you may see an advertisement for a Hawaii travel package on our sites or on another website you visit. 

Please note that we do not combine the information we collect about your travel-related searches on this website with personal information to display ads to you across other websites. You can choose not to receive customized online advertising on other websites, that is based on your travel-related searches on this website, through the [Network Advertising Initiative](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/) or the [Digital Advertising Alliance](http://www.aboutads.info/)

Advertising Data Collected By Business Partners and Ad Networks to Display Relevant Advertising to You   
The advertisements you see on the Travelocity Service are served by us or by our service providers. Third parties may collect information about your online activities through cookies and other technologies. We do not permit these third parties to collect personal information about you on our site. These third parties include (1) business partners, who collect information when you view or interact with one of their advertisements on our sites and (2) advertising networks, which collect information about your interests when you view or interact with one of the advertisements they place on many different websites on the Internet. The information gathered by these third parties is used to make predictions about you, your interests or preferences and to display advertisements on our sites and across the Internet tailored to your apparent interests. 

Please note that we do not have access to or control over cookies and other technologies these third parties may use to collect information about your interests, and the information practices of these third parties are not covered by this Privacy Policy. Some of these companies are members of the Network Advertising Initiative or the Digital Advertising Alliance, through which you may opt out of ad targeting from their member companies. To learn more, please visit [Network Advertising Initiative](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/) or the [Digital Advertising Alliance](http://www.aboutads.info/).

_Submitted Content_  
You can contribute to the Travelocity Service in a number of different ways, including by providing journals, recommendations, reviews, opinions, news articles, directories, guides, text, photographs, illustrations, graphics, logos, audio clips, images, information, data, photographs, software, messages, ideas, comments, questions, or other materials for public display on the Travelocity Service (your "Submitted Content"). Note that if you include personally identifiable information in your Submitted Content, it can be used and viewed by others. We are not responsible for the information you choose to include in your Submitted Content.

_Third Party Services_  
We may allow you to access third party services, such as Facebook and Twitter, that enable you to share your selected Submitted Content with those services, and import information about who you are connected with on those other services so you can connect with them using the Travelocity Service. Where we provide such functionality, such as on IgoUgo.com, you can always opt out on your IgoUgo account page. Some of those third party services may also provide us with information from your accounts there to enhance and personalize your use of the Travelocity Service. For example, you can allow Facebook to tell us who your Facebook friends are so you can follow their activity on the Travelocity Service (including on IgoUgo.com). You can, at any time, adjust your IgoUgo settings to remove this feature, by changing your Facebook preferences on the site. You can also further modify your privacy settings with those other services directly. For example, you can adjust your privacy settings on Facebook to prevent your Facebook friends from sharing information with us about you from their Facebook accounts.

_Location-specific information_  
If you use our location-enabled products and services, such as our mobile applications, you may be sending us location information. This information may reveal your actual location, such as GPS data, or it may not, such as when you submit an address to look at hotel choices in that location. We use your location information to process and personalize your requests, such as by pre-filling the city name when you are searching for a nearby hotel. We also use location information for support, to develop new features, a better user experience and to improve the overall quality of the Travelocity Service.

_Other_  
From time to time we may add or enhance services available using the Travelocity Service. To the extent these services are provided and used by you, we will use the information you provide to facilitate the service requested. For example, if you email us with a question, we will use information such as your email address, name and the nature of the question, to respond to your question. We may also store such information to assist us in making the Travelocity Service better and easier to use. 

With whom (if anyone) will my personal information be shared?  

When you book travel using the Travelocity Service, we provide to the airline, hotel, car-rental company, cruise line or other involved Third Party Supplier only that portion of your personal information that is needed for the successful fulfillment of your travel arrangements. We encourage you to read the privacy statements of all such Third Party Suppliers as their policies may be materially different from this Privacy Policy. We may also share personal information among our corporate affiliates at Sabre Holdings Corporation. For example, we book most of our travel services through the Sabre Global Distribution System, a leading processor of travel bookings worldwide which is operated by an affiliated company, and in doing so must provide certain of your personal information to them (as we would with any other GDS we now use or may use in the future). The Sabre privacy policy is available at <http://sabre-holdings.com/privacy/coreData.html>. When using a mobile device, note that all requests must be sent through your mobile carrier's or Wi-Fi provider's network and your carrier or provider may have access to the personal information being transmitted. For information regarding your carrier's or Wi-Fi provider's treatment of your personal information, please consult their applicable privacy policies. 

We use non-personal information in aggregate form to build higher quality, more useful online services by performing statistical analyses of the collective characteristics and behavior of our customers and visitors, and by measuring demographics and interests regarding specific areas of our site. We may provide anonymous statistical information based on this data to suppliers, advertisers, affiliates and other current and potential business partners. We may also use such aggregate data to inform these third parties as to the number of people who have seen and clicked on links to their web sites. Occasionally, Travelocity will hire a third party to act on our behalf for projects such as market-research surveys and contest-entry processing, or will contract with a third party to provide co-branded products, such as a Travelocity credit card. In such cases, Travelocity will provide information to these third parties specifically for use in connection with these projects. The information we provide to such third parties is protected by a confidentiality agreement and is to be used solely for the purpose(s) for which it has been provided. See "What other information should I know about my privacy?" below. 

How can I opt-out of receiving your promotional emails?  
Our Opt-out Policy  

As a Travelocity member and/or customer you will also occasionally receive updates from us about fare sales in your area, special offers, new Travelocity services, "Roaming Gnome Recommends", and other noteworthy items. We hope you will find these updates interesting and informative. Of course, if you would rather not receive a particular communication, please click on the "opt-out" link in our e-mail, or follow the instructions in each e-mail message. You can unsubscribe from our FareWatcher Plus service by editing your preferences in the FareWatcher Plus box of your "My Account" page. You may also unsubscribe from all Travelocity promotional communications, "Roaming Gnome Recommends", and FareWatcher Plus by clicking on the "unsubscribe" link in our e-mail. From time to time, we may use your personal information to send important notices, such as notifications about your trip or your account. Because this information is important to your interaction with Travelocity, you may not opt-out of receiving these communications. If using a mobile device, you may be able to configure the settings on the device not to provide location-specific information. However, if your device is configured to provide location-specific information, it is not possible at this time for you to opt-out of our gathering of such information via your mobile device. 

How can I update or correct my personal information?  

At any time, you can view and/or update your service preferences for our "Roaming Gnome Recommends", promotional e-mails, or FareWatcher Plus services. You can also update your personal profile, which includes member registration and travel preferences information, through "My Account" - accessible via "My Account" on the Travelocity home page. You may request that account information be deleted or deactivated for marketing purposes by e-mailing [privacy@travelocity.com](mailto:privacy@travelocity.com?Subject=Privacy%20Policy?Deactivate%20Account) and referencing the Privacy Policy-Deactivate Account in the subject line. Because of the way we maintain certain files, after you update your information or request that your account be deactivated for marketing purposes, residual copies of your information may remain in our active servers for a period of time and may remain in our backup systems. We may decline to process requests that are unreasonably repetitive, require disproportionate technical effort, jeopardize the privacy of others, or would be extremely impractical. Information may also be retained as required by law or for legitimate business purposes. 

What safeguards are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of your information?  

While no website can promise complete security, we have implemented administrative, technical, and physical security procedures designed to protect the personal information you provide to us. For example, only authorized employees are permitted to access personal information, and they may only do so for permitted business functions. In addition, we use encryption when transmitting your sensitive personal information between your system and ours, and we employ firewalls and intrusion detection systems to help prevent unauthorized persons from gaining access to your information. In addition, when you make travel purchases on Travelocity, you are protected by [Travelocity's Shop Safe Guarantee](http://www.travelocity.com/info/info_popup/0,,TRAVELOCITY%7CGUARANTEE_WINDOW,00.html). 

What other information should I know about my privacy?  

When using the Travelocity Service, you will see links to third party web sites, applications and services. Please note that when you click on one of these links, you will be using another company's web site, application or service. Except as set forth herein, we do not share your personal information with those third parties, and are not responsible for their privacy practices. We encourage you to read the privacy statements of all such sites as their policies may be materially different from this Privacy Policy. Of course, you are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your passwords and your Travelocity membership account information. Please be very careful, responsible, and alert with this information, especially whenever you're online. 

In addition to the circumstances described above, Travelocity may disclose personal information if required to do so by law, court order, as requested by other government or law enforcement authority, or in the good faith belief that disclosure is otherwise necessary or advisable including, without limitation, to protect the rights or properties of Travelocity or its affiliated companies or when we have reason to believe that disclosing the information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be causing interference with our rights or properties, whether intentionally or otherwise, or when anyone else could be harmed by such activities. In addition, if Travelocity or substantially all of its assets are acquired, the personal information of our customers will also most likely be transferred in connection with such acquisition. 

What we do NOT do: a warning about "phishing"  

We do not and will not, at any time, request your credit card information, login name, or password, in an unsecure or unsolicited e-mail or telephone communication.

Identity theft and the practice currently known as **"phishing"** are of great concern to us. Safeguarding information to help protect you from identity theft is our priority. For more information about phishing, you may want to visit the Federal Government website "OnGuard Online" at <http://onguardonline.gov/phishing.html>. 

This Privacy Policy was last revised on December 19, 2012. We may change or supplement this Privacy Policy from time to time. Any material changes in the way Travelocity uses personal information will be described in future versions of this Privacy Policy. Privacy Policy changes will apply to the information collected from the date we post the revised Privacy Policy, as well as to existing information held by us. If any proposed change is unacceptable to you, you may request that we remove your personal information from our records by e-mailing [privacy@travelocity.com](mailto:privacy@travelocity.com?Subject=Privacy%20Policy?Deactivate%20Account). Also, please review the information above under the heading "How can I update or correct my personal information?" Of course, you may always submit concerns regarding our Privacy Policy or our privacy practices via email by clicking on the same link. Please reference the privacy policy in your subject line. You can also write to us at: Travelocity, 3150 Sabre Drive, Southlake, Texas 76092 Attn: Privacy Team. 

_Thank you for using Travelocity Service!_
